Barskov Nikita

J+47 941 93 314 ⊠nbarskov@gmail.com Onikitabarskov mnikitabarskov

Introduction

Hi, I'm Nikita, 24 years old software developer from Russia. I live permanently in Oslo since 2019.

Most of most experience is related to work as a combined Data Engineer and Data Scientist position. I've set up and maintained several projects required as a data engineering part with integration and transforming part, and monitoring process, and as a data science part with data exploration, implementing models, doing experiments, and package models into a production solution.

I love to work with data, focus on solving relevant problems, and deliver maintainable solutions, satisfying business requirements.

My goal is to find the Data Engineer position in a product development company.

Experience

Rystad Energy, Oslo, Norway

Data Engineer / Data Scientist

September 2019 – present

My primary responsibility was to implement and maintain a data pipeline for different projects (maritime and road traffic monitoring applications, satellite imagery based projects).

Stack: Python, PyTorch/FastAl, Google Colab, Azure, Ansible, Linux, Prometheus, PostgreSQL, PostGlS, Docker.

Maxifier, Samara, Russia

Data Engineer

June 2017 – August 2019

I was developing the application for forecasting users' interactions with advertising content. The algorithm I used was a fundamental of my Master thesis. I was responsible for the integration, transforming, forecasting, and forecast quality evalution parts.

Stack: Python, Spark, Hadoop, Mesos, Docker, MySQL, Akka, Slick, SciPy, Maven, GitHub. Intern April 2017 – June 2017

Working on batch processing project in Maxifier as Intern.

Stack: Java, Guice, PostgreSQL, Spark, Hadoop, Aurora, Bazel, GitLab Cl.

Education

Samara University, Samara Russia

Master Degree Student

September 2017 - June 2019

Data Analysis and Quality Assurance, Average Point 5.0 (Excellent)

Bachelor of Science

Sep 2013 – June 2017

Applied Mathematics and Physics, Average Point 4.65 (Good)

Skills

Soft: focus on rational problem solving, flexible in communication, critical and responsible for my work, understand the importance of team working, and analysis of feedback

Base Skills: mathematics, physics, computer science

Natural Languages: Russian (motherlounge), English (intermediate) **Programming Languages:** Python 3 (primary language), Java/Scala

Frameworks and libraries: Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos, Docker, Scipy (Pandas,

Numpy, Matplotlib), spatial analysis libraries (fiona, rasterio, shapely, GeoPandas)

Build Tools and VCS: Poetry, Maven, Bazel, Git, Gitlab Cl, GitHub

Others: software development methodologies, QA, Bussiness and System Analytics